目前556号航道上太阳耀斑活动加剧
Solar flare activity has increased across Spacelanes 556
建议所有商业航班…
and all commercial flights are advised...
现在我们在公元20万年的一艘太空船上
So, it's 200, 000, it's a spaceship.
慢着 应该是空间站
No, wait a minute, space station.
还有
And...
去试试那边那扇门 快去吧
go try that gate over there! Off you go!
公元20万年吗 -没错
200,000? - 200,000.
亚当 快出来
Adam! Out you come.
我的天呐 -别激动 你会习惯的
Oh, my God... - Don't worry, you'll get used to it.
我们在哪 -问得好
Where are we? - Good question.
我看看
Let's see.
根据建筑风格
So, judging by the architecture,
我估计是公元20万年左右
I'd say we're around the year 200,000.
而且如果你仔细听的话
And if you listen...
发动机声
Engines.
所以我们估计是在某个空间站上
We're on some sort of space station.
没错 绝对是空间站
Yeah, definitely a space station.
挺热啊 暖气就不能调低些吗
It's a bit warm in here, they could turn the heating down.
这么着 咱们去试试那边的门 来
Tell you what, let's try that gate. Come on.
到了
Here we go.
这就是
And this is...
我还是让博士来解释给你听吧
I'll let the Doctor describe it.
伟大富强的人类第四帝国 就是那了
The Fourth Great and Bountiful Human Empire. And there it is.
行星地球 处在全盛时期
Planet Earth, at its height.
全球遍布超级大都市
Covered with mega-cities,
有五个卫星 人口960亿
five moons, population 96 billion,
是全银河的中心 统治着亿万颗行星
the hub of a galactic domain stretching across a million planets,
亿万个种族 人类居于统治地位
a million species, with mankind right in the middle.
这就是你男朋友
He's your boyfriend.
不再是了
Not any more.
神秘博士第一季第七集
漫长的游戏
来吧亚当 敞开你的头脑 你会喜欢的
Come on, Adam, open your mind. You'll like this.
这是最辉煌的历史时期
Fantastic period of history,
人类的智慧达到了鼎盛
the human race at its most intelligent.
无论是文化 艺术还是政治
Culture! Art! Politics!
这个时期饮食丰盛
This era has got fine food,
人民文明有礼 成就… -滚开
good manners, the works... - Out the way!
有人吗 -你想要点什么
Somebody there? - What do you want, love?
别挡道
Keep it moving.
我稍后就来招待您 -一个一个来
I'll be with you lot in a minute. - One at a time!
你想要什么 客隆芝士堡
Now what was it? Kronkburger with cheese,
还是客隆薯芋茄堡
kronkburger with pajatos?
喂 哥们 别挤
Oi! You, mate! Stop pushing.
后面排队去 我说了 后面去
Get back! I said back!
这还叫饮食丰盛 -我的表又不准了
Fine cuisine? - My watch must be wrong.
很准啊 奇怪了
No, it's fine. That's weird.
叫你再显摆
That's what comes showing off.
你的历史也不像你以为的那么好
Your history's not as good as you thought it was.
我的历史没问题 -显然你错了
My history is perfect. - Obviously not.
他们全都是人类 可那些
They're all human. What about
亿万星球 亿万种族都哪去了
the millions of planets, the millions of species?
问得好 别说你还真问着了
Good question. Actually that IS a good question.
亚当 老伙计 你肯定饿坏了
Adam, me old mate, you must be starving!
不 我只是需要倒时差
No, I'm just a bit timesick.
你就是饿了 一个客隆堡多少钱
You just need grub. How much is a kronkburger?
2.2信用点 亲爱的 排队去
Two credits twenty, sweetheart. Now join the queue!
钱 我们需要钱
Money! We need money.
去找自动提款机去
Let's use a cashpoint.
5信用点
出钞中
给 拿去零花 别全买糖吃了
There you go, pocket money. Don't spend it all on sweets.
这怎么花啊
Well, how does it work?
自己去研究啊 缠着我做什么
Go and find out, stop nagging me!
是这样亚当 时间旅行就像去逛巴黎
The thing is, Adam, time travel's like visiting Paris.
光看看旅游指南可不够
You can't just read the guidebook.
你得亲身去体验 亲自品尝美食
You've got to throw youself in, eat the food,
结结巴巴说法语
use the wrong verbs,
花冤枉钱 以及去吻陌生人
get charged double and kiss complete strangers.
还是说只有我是这样
Or is that just me?
别问问题了 去玩吧
Stop asking questions, go and do it!
快去吧 初次约会呢
Off you go then. Your first date.
瞧瞧你那欠抽的表情
You're gonna get a smack, you are!
我知道听起来有点傻 但能否告诉我我在哪
Erm, this is gonna sound daft, but can you tell me where I am?
139层
Floor 139.
标志牌再大就撑出去了 -哪里的楼层
Could they write it any bigger? - Floor 139 of what?
看来你真喝晕了
Must've been a hell of a party.
你在五号卫星上 -五号卫星是什么
You're on Satellite Five. - And what's Satellite Five?
得了吧 你既然不知道这是哪
Come on. How could you get on board
那你怎么上来了 -我傻呗
without knowing where you are? - Look at me, I'm stupid!
慢着慢着 您是调查员吗
Hold on, wait a minute. . . Are you a test?
上头派下来访查的 -被你看穿了
Some sort of management test kind of thing? - You've got me!
好眼力 果然骗不了你
Well done! You're too clever for me.
基础培训里就提醒过我们
We were warned about this in basic training.
所有员工必须精通推广公司形象
All workers have to be versed in company promotion.
好 问吧 有什么问题尽管问
Right, fire away, ask your questions.
只要能提拔我到500层 我做什么都行
If it gets me to Floor 500, I'll do anything.
为什么 500层是什么
Why? What happens on Floor 500?
那里的墙是金子做的
The walls are made of gold!
你该清楚得很 管理层大人
And you should know, Mr. Management.
我们就是干这个的
So... this is what we do.
最新资讯 沙暴袭击维纳斯群岛
Latest news! Sandstorms on the New Venus Archipelago,
致200人死亡
200 dead.
格拉斯哥缺水暴动进入第三天
Glasgow water riots into their third day.
77号太空航道因太阳黑子活动关闭
Spacelane 77 closed by sunspot activity.
在恶狼频道
Over on the Bad Wolf channel,
伯欧之脸刚刚宣布他怀孕了
The Face of Boe has just announced he's pregnant.
我懂了 你们广播新闻
I get it. You broadcast the news.
我们就是新闻
We ARE the news.
我们都是记者
We're the journalists.
我们写新闻 编排好再卖出去
We write it, package it and sell it.
600个频道 全都播发自
600 channels, all coming out
五号卫星 把信号输送到每个角落
of Satellite Five, broadcasting everywhere.
有件事
Something...
不对劲
is wrong.
有些不真实
Something fictional.
那几个人
Those people.
整个人类帝国的所有动静
Nothing happens in the whole Human Empire
都别想逃过我们的眼睛
without it going through us.
做安全检查
Security check.
仔细查
Go deep.
全体员工请注意 零售用餐区
'All staff are reminded that the canteen area
将启动自清洁程序 谢谢
now operates a self-cleaning table system. Thank you.'
尝尝这个 这个叫扎菲克
Try this, it's called zaffic.
很好喝 就像 像雪泥一样
It's nice, like, erm, a Slush Puppy.
什么味儿的
What flavour?
有点儿牛肉味
It's sort of beef.
我的天呐
Oh, my God!
就好像一切都不在了
It's like everything's gone.
家园 家人
Home, family. . .
一切都没了
Everything.
这个能帮到你 博士做了点升级
This helps. The Doctor gave it a bit of a top-up.
你家有谁 你爸妈吗
Who's back home, your mum and dad?
是啊
Yeah.
给他们打电话吧
Phone 'em up.
但那是19万8千年之前了
But that's 198, 000 years ago.
我说真的 试试吧 来吧
Honestly, try it. Go on.
打给地球还要拨地区码吗 -赶紧拨
Is there a code for planet Earth? - Just dial!
抱歉我们不在家 -是我家
'I'm sorry, we're not in.' - It's home!
请留言 谢谢 再见
'Please leave a message. Thanks, bye!'
是…是我
It... it's me.
我去旅游去了
'I've sort of gone travelling.
我遇见了几个人 一起游历去了
'I met these people and we're travelling together,'
不过我挺好的 回头再打给你们
but, I'm fine. And I'll call you later.
爱你们 再见
Love you. Bye.
你们两个小笨蛋 过来
Oi, Mutt and Jeff! Over 'ere!
检查完毕 无隐患 -不对 有问题
'Security check cleared.' - No, something's wrong!
我能感觉到
I can taste it.
信息流中有一点不对劲
A tiny little shift in the information.
某些人不该在这里
Someone down there shouldn't be here.
再次检查
Double check.
三次检查
Triple check.
盯紧他们
Follow them.
大家都注意了 上头派人来检查工作了
Now everybody behave, we have a management inspection.
您想怎么办 按规定来吗
How d'you want it, by the book?
从头开始吧 多谢
Right from scratch, thanks.
很好 那么各位女士先生
OK. So! Ladies, gentlemen,
各位多性人 未知性人和机器人
multisex, undecided or robot,
我是卡西卡·珊提尼·卡戴尼
my name is Cathica Santini Khadeni.
是卡片的卡 万一您
That's Cathica with a C,
您要是向500层写报告表扬我请不要客气
in case you want to write to Floor 500, praising me. And please do.
请您随意提问吧
Now, please feel free to ask any questions.
新闻采访流程是绝对公开
The process of news gathering must be open,
诚实和无偏见的
honest and beyond bias.
这是本公司的一贯政策
That's company policy.
其实法律也这么规定了
Actually, it's the law.
多谢你了 苏琪
Yes, thank you, Suki.
好 大家别紧张
OK, keep it calm.
别在贵宾面前出丑
Don't show off for the guests.
开始吧
Here we go.
准备
And...
启动安全系统
engage safety.
三
And three...
二 开始
two... and spike!
压缩信息流
Compressed information.
灌进她的大脑
Streaming into her!
来自每个城市 国家 甚至星球的信息
Reports from every city, every country, every planet,
全都打包输送进了她的头脑
and they all get packaged inside her head.
她成为了这软件的一部分
She becomes part of the software.
她的大脑就是电脑
Her brain IS the computer!
如果她掌握这么多消息 那肯定是个天才
If it all goes through her, she must be a genius.
不 她什么都不会记住
Nah, she wouldn't remember any of it.
太多了 她的脑袋会炸了的
There's too much. Her head'd blow up!
大脑只是处理器
The brain's the processor.
结束之后她就全忘了
Soon as it closes, she forgets.
那边上这一圈人是做什么的
What about these people round the edge?
他们的头脑里都植入了微型芯片
They've all got tiny little chips in their head,
使他们和她连接起来 进行转播
connecting them to her. And they transmit.
600个频道
600 channels.
全帝国大事小情都从这里播发出去
Every single fact in the Empire beams out of this place.
我说这才叫权力
Now that's what I call power.
分析确认 存在安全漏洞
'Analysis confirmed. Security breach.'
我就知道 是哪一个
I knew it! Which one?
肯定就是那屋子里的一个 是谁
It's someone inside that room, which one?
分析漏洞中
'Isolating breach.'
来啊 给我看看 是谁
Come on. Show me! Who is it?
你还好吗 -我能看见她的脑子
You all right? - I can see her brain.
你想出去吗 -不 但是这个
D'you wanna get out? - No, but this...
这个技术 太惊人了
this technology, it's... amazing.
这个技术有问题
This technology's wrong.
有麻烦吗
Trouble?
对
Oh, yeah.
就是她
That's it! Ho, ho, ho, yes!
她就是撒谎的那一个 截断传输然后扫描
She's the liar! Intercept and scan.
抓到你啦
Gotcha!
拜托 苏琪 还没到一半 你这是干嘛
Come off it, Suki, I wasn't even halfway! What was that for?
抱歉 一定是哪里出了故障
Sorry. It must've been a glitch.
她的信息被篡改了
Her information's been tampered with.
里面掩藏着另一个身份
There's a second biography hidden underneath.
好的 阁下 那是一定的 阁下
Yes, sir. Absolutely, sir.
对 她的信息被加密了
Yeah, her data was encrypted,
所以我们没办法早点发现
so there's no way we could've found her sooner.
抱歉 抱歉 阁下
Yeah, sorry, I... yeah, sorry, sir.
好的 绝对的
Yeah, absolutely.
把她弄上来 赶紧
Get her up here! Now!
人员晋升
Promotion.
来吧 机会来了 加油
Come on, this is it, come on!
天呐 一定要是我
Oh, my God, make it me!
来吧 说出我的名字 说出我的名字
Come on, say my name, say my name, say my name!
晋升人员为
Promotion for...
苏琪·马克雷·坎特尔 请前往500层
Suki Macrae Cantrell. Please proceed to floor 500.
真不敢相信 500层
I don't believe it! Floor 500!
你是怎么做到的 我可是你的上级
How the hell did you manage that? I'm above you!
我不知道 我只是抱着微弱的希望申请了
I don't know, I just applied on the off chance.
然后居然通过了
And they've said yes!
真不公平
Oh, it's so not fair,
我已经连续申请了三年了
I've been applying to Floor 500 for three years!
500层是什么
What's Floor 500?
那里的墙是金子做的
The walls are made of gold.
卡西卡 我会想你的
Cathica, I'm gonna miss you.
500层 谢谢你 -我什么都没做
Floor 500! Thank you! - I didn't do anything!
你是我的幸运符
You're my lucky charm!
好吧 我不介意拥抱任何人
All right, I'll hug anyone!
放松点 没那么可怕
Come on, it's not that bad.
什么 头上那玩意儿吗
What? With the... the head-thing?!
对 但她已经关起来了
Yeah, well, she's closed it now.
对 但是
Yeah, but...
这里的一切 我都有些接受不了
It's everything. It freaks me out.
我需要…
And I just need to...
如果我能…
ah, if I could just...
冷静一下 适应这里
cool down. Sort of acclimatise.
什么意思
How d'you mean?
也许我回观景台里坐着会比较好
Maybe I could just go and sit on the observation deck.
可以吗
Would that be all right?
学着融入 假装自己是公元20万年的公民
Soak it in, y'know. Pretend I'm a citizen of the year 200, 000.
你需要我陪你吗
D'you want me to come with ya?
不 不 你陪着博士吧
No, no, you stick with the Doctor.
你一定更想和他在一起
You'd rather be with him.
要介入你们之间 我还不够格
It's gonna take a better man than me to get between you two.
总之
Anyway...
我就在观景台等你们
I'll be on the deck.
来 拿着塔迪斯的钥匙
Here you go, take the Tardis key.
要是适应不了这里可以回去
Just in case it gets a bit too much.
好 说得好像塔迪斯就不奇怪一样
Yeah, like it's not weird in there.
我该走了 不能让他们等我 抱歉
Oh my God, I've got to go! I can't keep them waiting. I'm sorry!
替我向斯蒂夫告别
Say goodbye to Steve for me.
再见
Bye!
终于摆脱她了
Good riddance!
听着好像你再也不会见到她了
You're talking like you'll never see her again.
她不就上个楼吗
She's only gone upstaris.
确实见不到了 去了500层的就不回来了
We won't. Once you go to Floor 500, you never come back.
你上去过吗 -去不了
Have you ever been up there? - Can't.
坐电梯需要钥匙
You need a key for the lift,
只有晋升了才会有钥匙
and you only get a key with promotion.
没人能上500层 除了那少数的中选者
No-one gets to 500, except for the chosen few.
你是谁
Who are you?
我是编辑
I'm the Editor.
怎么回事
What's happening?
外面有尸体 到底是怎么回事
There are bodies out there. What's going on?
既然进入了提问环节
While we're asking questions,
你能再说下你的姓名吗
would you please confirm your name?
我叫苏琪·马克雷·坎特尔
'My name is Suki Macrae Cantrell. I was
199…89年出生于摩洛哥独立共和国
born 199 apostrophe 89 in the Independent Republic of Morocco.'
骗子
Liar!
兴趣是阅读和建筑学
'Hobbies include reading and archaeology.
两方面都不算专家 我只是热爱钻研
'I'm not an expert or anything, I just like digging.'
骗子
Liar!
我想为五号卫星工作
'I want to work for Satellite Five
因为我妹妹没钱上大学
because my sister can't afford university,
而你们的待遇实在很好 -骗子
'and the pay-scheme is really good...' - Liar!
让我们来看看事实是怎样的吧
Let's look at the facts, shall we?
掩藏在基因移植下 却仍然是你
Hidden behind a genetic graft, but that's still you.
伊娃·圣·朱莉安 十五自由人中的幸存者
Eva Saint Julienne, last surviving member of the Freedom Fifteen.
号称无政府主义者 对吗
Mmm, self-declared anarchist, is that right?
五号卫星受谁控制
Who controls Satellite Five?
这就是你的回答
There's the truth!
自由组织一直
The Freedom Foundation has
在监控着五号卫星的传输
been monitoring Satellite Five's transmissions.
我们有确实证据证明事实被人操纵着
We have absolute proof that the facts are being manipulated.
你们在对人类撒谎
You are lying to the people!
我真喜欢 再说一遍
Oooh, I love it! Say it again!
这整个系统是腐败的
This whole system is corrupt.
你为谁工作
Who do you represent?
我只是一个小小的奴隶
I'm merely a humble slave.
我服从总编辑的命令
I answer to the Editor In Chief.
他是谁 他在哪里 -他俯瞰着一切
Who is he, where is he? - He's overseeing everything.
实实在在的一切
Literally everything.
你不介意的话 我要问问上头这位的意见了
If you don't mind, I'm gonna have to refer this upwards.
那是什么 -你的老板
What is that? - Your boss.
它一直都是你的老板
This has always been your boss.
从你出生那天起
Since the day you were born.
请给我访问权限
Give me access.
请给我
Give me...
我能学到任何事
I can learn anything.
试试 计算机
Let's try, erm, computers.
从二十一世纪到今天
From the 21st century to the present day,
给我微型处理器的历史
give me the history of the microprocessor.
天呐
Oh my God.
他们只给我二十分钟休养
Look, they only give us twenty minutes maintenance,
你不能消停一会吗
can't you give it a rest?
但你从没去过其他楼层 哪怕是楼下一层吗
But you've never been to another floor? Not even one floor down?
我刚来时去过16层
I went to Floor 16 when I first arrived,
那是医疗部门 在我的头上安装芯片的地方
that's Medical, that's where I got my head done
然后我 我就直接来这里了
and then I...I came straight here.
在五号卫星上
Satellite Five. You work,
工作 吃饭 睡觉都在同一层 就这样
eat and sleep on the same floor, that's it, that's all.
你不是管理层吧
You're not management, are you?
终于明白了 还算聪明
At last, she's clever!
不管是什么 别扯上我 我什么都不知道
Whatever it is, don't involve me. I don't know anything.
你为什么不问 -我为什么要问
Don't you even ask? - Why would I?
因为你是记者呀
You're a journalist!
为什么所有工作人员都是人类
Why's all the crew human?
那又怎么样
What's that got to do with anything?
卫星上没有外星人 为什么
There's no aliens on board. Why?
不知道 没有特定的原因
I dunno, no real reason.
他们没有被禁止进入 -那他们在哪里
They're not banned or anything. - Then where are they?
我猜移民政策变紧了
I suppose immigration's tightened up.
因为那些危机的关系
It's had to, with all the threats.
什么危机
What threats?
不知道 所有那些 常见的危机
I dunno, all of them. Usual stuff.
空间旅行费用加倍 所以很多游客来不了了
The price of spacewarp doubled, so that kept the visitors away.
而且查维克·法斯星球上的政府崩溃了
Oh, and the government on Chavic Fice collapsed,
所以他们无法来了
so that lot stopped coming, you see?
这样那样的小原因 没别的
Just lots of little reasons, that's all.
这些都指向了一个事实 而你居然没注意到
Adding up to one great big fact. And you didn't even notice.
博士 如果有任何阴谋的话
Doctor, I think if there was any sort of conspiracy,
五号卫星会知道的
Satellite Five would have seen it.
我们能看到一切 -我能看到更多
We see everything. - I can see better.
这个社会是畸形的
This society's the wrong shape,
包括这些科技 -这是最精尖的
even the technology. - It's cutting edge!
这简直是倒退 你脑袋上有个洞
It's backwards. There's a great big door in your head!
你们早该抛弃这种技术了
You should've chucked this out years ago!
你认为发生了什么
So what you think is going on?
不只是这个太空站
It's not just this space station,
是整个态度 人们的思考方式
it's the whole attitude, it's the way people think.
伟大而慷慨的人类帝国
The great and bountiful human empire stunted,
有什么阻止了它的发展
something's holding it back.
你怎么会知道
And how would you know?
相信我 人类倒退回九十年前了
Trust me, humanity's been set back about 90 years.
五号卫星从什么时候开始广播的
When did Satellite Five start broadcasting?
九十一年前
91 years ago.
爸妈 留着这条留言
Mum, Dad, keep this message, OK?
无论如何不要删除
Whatever you do, don't erase it.
保存起来 知道吗
Save it, you got that?
微处理器从2019年开始变得累赘
The microprocessor became redundant in the year 2019,
被一种叫SMT的系统所替代
replaced by a system called SMT
也就是单分子转录系统
the Single Molecule Transcription.
十六层
不 不 不 你怎么了
No, no, no, no, no! What are you doing?
回来 怎么会这样
Come back, come... Why are you doing that?
十六层是什么 那里有什么
What's Floor 16? What's down there?
不好意思
Sorry...
十六层 你们涵盖什么业务
Floor 16, that's... What do you cover?
非紧急医疗服务
Medical non-emergency.
对 走错了 我有些技术上的问题
Right! Wrong floor. I'm having technical difficulties,
屏幕一直不动 拒绝我的访问
my screen keeps freezing, locking me out.
不 那就是医疗问题
No, that's medical.
一定是你的芯片出了问题
There must be something wrong with your chip.
对 当然了 对
Yes! Yeah, of course, yeah!
我没有芯片
I haven't got one.
难怪你不能访问系统
No wonder you can't get a screen to work.
你是什么人 学生吗
What are you, a... student?
对 对
Yes. Yeah, I'm, erm...
我正在进行
I'm on a research project...
一个火星大学的科研项目
from the University of Mars.
火星人的行为艺术 太典型了
The Martian boondocks, typical.
确实
Yep!
但你还是需要植入芯片
Well, you still need chipping.
那就意味着
So, does that mean, like...
脑部手术吗 -这说法很古老
brain surgery? - That's an old-fashioned phrase,
但就是那个意思
but it's the same thing, yes.
没关系
Oh! OK. Never mind.
如果我有了芯片
But if I get a chip,
我就可以用任何一台电脑吗
that means I could use any computer?
当然
Absolutely.
你需要付费
You'll have to pay for it.
他们已经停止补贴了
They've stopped subsidising.
好的 抱歉 耽误了你的时间
Oh, right, sorry. Wasting your time.
多谢
Thanks.
等等
Hold on!
我能用这个吗
Can I use this?
完全可以
That'll do nicely.
总的来说 共有两种基本类型
It all comes down to two basic types.
第一种 头部芯片
Type one, the head-chip,
植入头骨后部 一百信用点
inserted into the back of the skull, one hundred credits.
这就是芯片
There's the chip.
微小 肉眼不可见 术后无疤
Tiny, invisible, no scarring.
第二种 完全信息导入
Type two is the full info-spike.
就是那…
That's the...
玩意儿 -就是那个
thing. - That's the one.
需要一万信用点
It does cost 10,000.
我…我可付不起这么多
Oh, well I... I couldn't afford it then.
完全不会 刚发现你有无限信用点
Not at all. Turns out you've got unlimited credit.
不 我…我不做这手术
No, but I... well, I couldn't have it done.
那肯定 很疼吧
I mean... that's gotta hurt, isn't it?
无痛手术 合同保障
Painless. Contractual guarantee.
不了 我的同伴还在楼上等我
No, my... my mate's waiting upstairs,
我可做不了大手术
I can't have major surgery.
只要十分钟
It takes ten minutes.
你有这么多钱 就能做快速微创手术
That sort of money buys a very fast picosurgeon.
不了 我…
No, but I...
我还是不做了
I couldn't though, no.
第一种 你可以和简单电脑进行交互
Type one, you can interface with a simple computer.
第二种 你自己就是电脑
Type two, you ARE the computer.
你能传输五号卫星上的任何存储信息
You can transmit any piece of information from the archive of Satellite Five,
基本上可以说 就是全人类的整个历史
which is just about the entire history of the human race.
现在
Now...
你想选哪一种
which one's it going to be?
我们肯定要有麻烦了
We're so gonna get in trouble.
谁都不可以碰主机 我们会被训斥的
You're not allowed to touch the mainframe, we'll get told off.
洛斯 让她闭嘴
Rose, tell her to button it.
你不能破坏这里 别人会发现的
You can't vandalise the place, someone's gonna notice!
我不明白
I don't understand!
我们做了全面的安全扫描
We did a full security scan.
我们揪出苏琪·马克雷·坎特尔的时候他也在
That man was there when we found Suki Macrae Cantrell.
并未检出他有任何异常
There were no indications about him.
但是他却有问题
And yet here he is.
显然是脱离了系统检测范围
Clearly acting outside the parameters.
太有趣了
Fascinating!
遵命 阁下
Yes, sir!
没问题
Absolutely!
这就去
At once!
检查他
Check him.
二次检查 三次检查 四次检查
Double check him, triple check him, quadruple!
我不掺和这事了 我要回去干活
This is nothing to do with me, I'm going back to work.
那你走吧 再见
Go on then, see ya!
我可不能就丢下你们不管
I can't just leave you, can I?
如果你真想帮忙
If you want to be useful,
那就让他们调低点温度 快热死了
get them to turn the heating down, it's boiling.
这儿到底怎么回事 没人来看看吗
What's wrong with this place? Can't they do something about it?
不知道 我们也一直问
I don't know. We keep asking.
好像是涡轮机出了问题
Something to do with the turbines.
"Something to do with the turbines".
我又不知道 -确实
I don't know! - Exactly.
我对你不抱希望了 卡西卡
I give up on you, Cathica.
你瞧瞧洛斯
Now, Rose, look at Rose.
洛斯才是问对了问题
Rose is asking the right kind of questions.
谢谢夸奖 -为什么这里这么热
I thank you. - Why is it so hot?
刚刚你还在担心这个帝国
One minute you worry about the Empire,
现在又关心中央空调问题了
the next it's the central heating!
永远别小瞧这些管道 它们可重要了
Oh, never underestimate plumbing. Plumbing is very important.
安全检查完毕
Security scan complete.
他是谁 -他谁都不是
Well, who is he? - He is no-one.
这算是什么名堂
What does THAT mean?
他谁都不是
He is no-one.
你是说他用了假身份吗
What, you mean he has a fake ID?
他没有身份
He has no identification.
但所有人都登记过身份
But everyone's registered.
我们有整个帝国的人口数据
We have a census for the entire Empire!
他谁都不是
He is no-one.
什么 他不存在吗
What, he doesn't exist?
任何地方都不存在吗 -他谁都不是
Not anywhere? - He is no-one.
那个金发女孩呢
What about the blonde?
她谁都不是 -两个人都这样
She is no-one. - BOTH of them?!
我们都清楚该如何处理无身份的人
Well, we all know what happens to non-entities.
他们要升权限了
They get promoted.
带他们上来
Bring them up!
找到了 五号卫星
Here we go. Satellite Five.
所有管道 这是结构图
Pipes and plumbing. Look at the layout.
太荒谬了
This is ridiculous.
你居然有权限进入电脑核心
You've got access to the computer's core.
你可以浏览文档 新闻 股票交易
You could look at the archive, the news, the stock exchange. . .
可你却在看管道 -因为出了问题
And you're looking at pipes? - But there's something wrong.
我猜是… -怎么了 是哪的问题
I suppose... - Why, what is it?
通风系统
The ventilation system.
冷风系统和制冷中枢都在高负荷运作
Cooling ducts. Ice filters. All working flat out.
都在向下传输大量热量
Channelling massive amounts of heat down.
都是从顶楼传来的 -第五百层
All the way from the top. - Floor 500.
上面的某个玩意儿不断产生巨大的热量
Something up there is generating tons and tons of heat.
不知道你们怎么想
Well, I don't know about you
我觉得我肯定是错过了派对
but I feel I'm missing out on a party.
楼上在举行派对
It's all going on upstairs.
一起上去吗 -上不去 得要钥匙
Fancy a trip? - You can't, you need a key.
钥匙就只是密码
Keys are just codes.
我已经拿到密码了 看好
And I've got the codes right here. Here we go.
超级权限 215.9
Override 215.9.
你怎么能拿到密码
How come it's giving YOU the code?
看来楼上有人喜欢我
Someone up there likes me.
我早说过是无痛的
I told you it was painless.
没有伤疤 你也看到了
No scarring, you see?
手术非常成功
Perfect success.
那我要怎么激活
How do I... activate it?
由你自己决定
It's a personal choice.
有些人是吹口哨激活
Some people whistle.
我认识一个人是通过
I know one man who triggers it
唱丹尼男孩来激活
with "Oh, Danny Boy".
但现在你的是默认设置
But you're set on default for now.
也就是打个响指
That's a click of the fingers.
你是说我只要…
You mean I just...?
打个响指
Click.
来吧 跟我们一起 -想都别想
Come on, come with us. - No way!
拜拜 -别提我的名字
Bye! - Well, don't mention my name.
你们要是遇到麻烦 别扯上我就行
When you get in trouble, just don't involve me.
她走了 亚当也没来
That's her gone. Adam's given up.
看来就我和你两个人了
Looks like it's just you and me.
对 -挺好
Yeah. - Good.
的确
Yep.
我的天呐 我有点想吐
Oh, my God! I'm gonna be sick!
特别赠送
Special offer.
我们还给你植入了呕吐自动处理系统
We installed the vomit-o-matic at the same time.
在你的喉咙内壁植入了微型白蚁
Nano-termites have been placed in the lining of your throat.
一旦你想要呕吐
In the event of sickness...
它们就把呕吐物冻结起来
they freeze the waste.
这儿的墙并不是金子制成的
The walls are not made of gold.
你应该回楼下去
You should go back downstairs.
才不要
Tough.
没等你们来 我先开始了
I started without you.
这实在太有趣了
This is fascinating.
五号卫星存有每一条
Satellite Five contains every piece of
伟大富强的人类第四帝国的信息
information within the Fourth Great and Bountiful Human Empire.
出生证明 购物习惯
Birth certificates, shopping habits,
银行账户 但你们俩
bank statements, but you two...
却不存在
you don't exist.
没有丝毫痕迹
There's not a trace.
没有出生证明 没有工作 全都没有
No birth, no job, not the slightest kiss.
你们怎么做到行走于世界却不留下一点踪迹的
How can you walk through the world and not leave a single footprint?
苏琪 苏琪
Suki... Suki!
你能听见我说话吗 苏琪
Hello? Can you hear me? Suki?
你对她做了什么 -我想她已经死了
What have you done to her? - I think she's dead.
但她仍在工作
But she's... working.
他们的脑子里都是芯片
They've all got chips in their head.
是芯片在继续工作 就像傀儡一样
And the chips keep going. Like puppets.
你知道得可真多啊
You're full of information,
但你也得给我些你的信息才公平
but it's only fair we get some information back.
因为很显然 你谁都不是
Because, apparently, you're no-one.
还有我不知道的事 真是太稀奇了
It's so rare, not to know something.
你到底是谁
Who are you?
这并不重要 因为我们要走了
It doesn't matter, cos we're off.
很高兴见到你 走吧
Nice to meet you. Come on!
告诉我你们是谁
Tell me who you are!
既然这信息能让我们活命
Since that information's keeping us alive,
那我就更不能说了
I'm hardly gonna say, am I?
也许我的总编辑能够说服你
Well, perhaps my Editor In Chief can convince you otherwise.
是谁
And who's that?
也许你会有兴趣知道
It may interest you to know that
这里并不是伟大富强的人类第四帝国
this is NOT the Fourth Great and Bountiful Human Empire.
其实跟人类完全没有关系
In fact, it's not actually human at all.
只是碰巧有人类居住罢了
It's merely a place where humans happen to live.
好的 好的
Yep. Yep.
抱歉
Sorry!
是我的客户好心让人类
It's a place where humans are allowed to live,
在这儿居住的
by kind permission of my client.
那是什么
What is that?
你是说那玩意掌控着五号卫星吗
You mean that thing's in charge of Satellite Five?
你所谓的"玩意"可是掌控着全人类
That "thing", as you put it, is in charge of the human race.
人类接受了差不多一百年的塑造和引导
For almost 100 years, mankind has been shaped and guided.
他们的知识和野心
His knowledge and ambition,
完全被新闻报道所控制
strictly controlled, by its broadcast news.
而这些新闻都是由我的上级
Edited by my superior,
你们的主人发布的
your master,
他是人类的指引之光
and humanity's guiding light,
来自神圣哈杰西马科斯多佛的伟大加戈菲斯
The Mighty Jagrafess of the Holy Hadrojassic Maxarodenfoe.
我称它为马科斯
I call him Max!
只要制造出恐惧气氛 就能轻易封锁边境
Create a climate of fear, and it's easy to keep the borders closed.
这仅仅取决于报道强度
It's just a matter of emphasis.
在合适的新闻里用上合适的词语
The right word in the right broadcast
重复得多了甚至能破坏经济
repeated often enough can destabilise an economy.
创造敌人 改变选票
Invent an enemy. Change a vote.
所以全地球的人都是奴隶吗
So all the people on Earth are like... slaves?
这倒是个很有趣的看法
Well, now, there's an interesting point.
如果奴隶不知道自己被奴役了
Is a slave a slave if he doesn't know
他还是奴隶吗 - 是的
he's enslaved? - Yes.
我还以为会进行一场哲学性辩论呢
Oh, I was hoping for a philosophical debate.
结果你就回答个"是的"
Is that all I'm gonna get? "Yes"?
是的
Yes.
你一点也不好玩
You're no fun.
松开这副手铐 你就会发现我有多好玩
Let me out of these manacles. You'll find out how much fun I am.
看来他挺难对付的嘛
Oh, he's tough, isn't he?!
说真的 这套系统很棒吧
But come on! Isn't it a great system?
不管怎么样 也会敬佩一下吧
You've got to admire it, just a bit.
这么大个玩意儿哪藏得住
You can't hide something on this scale,
肯定会被人发现的
somebody must've noticed.
确实有时候会被人发现
From time to time, someone, yes.
但电脑芯片系统允许我入侵他们的大脑
But the computer-chip system allows me to see inside their brains.
有一点非分之想我都能发现
I can see the smallest doubt.
然后摧毁它
And crush it!
然后他们就继续过他们的生活
And then they just carry on, living the life,
和楼下全世界的人们
strutting about downstairs
一起盎然阔步 得意洋洋
and all over the surface of the Earth,
以为自己独一无二
like they're SO individual.
其实他们一点也不
When, of course, they're not.
他们就只是牲口
They're just cattle.
这么说来 加戈菲斯其实什么也没改变
In that respect, the Jagrafess hasn't changed a thing.
那你呢 你又不是加戈 肥死什么的
But what about you? You're not a Jagra... er... belly.
加戈菲斯 -加戈菲斯
Jagrafess. - Jagrafess.
你又不是加戈菲斯
You're not a Jagrafess.
你也是人类 -是没错
You're human. - Yeah, well,
但仅仅作为人类赚的钱太少了
simply being human doesn't pay very well.
但你不可能一个人全搞定 -当然不可能
But you couldn't have done this all on your own. - No!
我是银行联盟的代表
I represent a consortium of banks.
金钱更适合于长线投资
Money prefers a long-term investment.
而且加戈菲斯也需要别人帮它
Also the Jagrafess needed a little hand,
安装好自己
to, install himself.
可不是嘛 这么大个怪物
No wonder, creature that size.
它寿命有多长
What's its lifespan?
三千年 -它的新陈代谢太猛烈了
3,000 years. - That's one hell of a metabolism.
产生如此多的热量
Generating all that heat.
所以五号卫星才这么热
That's why Satellite Five's so hot.
你把热量从怪物体内抽出来
You pump it out of the creature,
传送到楼下
channel it downstairs,
加戈菲斯就能凉爽地活下去
Jagrafess stays cool, stays alive.
五号卫星就是个庞大的生命维持系统
Satellite Five is one great big life-support system.
又是我 千万别删除留言
Me again. Don't wipe this message.
听上去可能就只是段噪音
It's just gonna sound like white noise,
但保存好 因为我能听懂
but save it, cos I can translate it, OK?
三 二 一 开始
Three, two, one, and spike!
所以你们对我来说是个威胁
But THAT'S why you're so dangerous.
知识就是力量 而我对你们却一无所知
Knowledge is power, but you remain unknown.
你们到底是谁
Who are you?
放了她 我是博士 她是洛斯·泰勒
Leave her alone! I'm the Doctor. She's Rose Tyler,
我们只是无名小卒 闲逛到了这
we're nothing, we're just wandering.
你们到底是谁 -我刚说了
Tell me who you are! - I've just said!
那你们为谁工作
Yeah, but who do you work for?
谁派你们来的 谁知道我们的事
Who sent you? Who knows about us?
到底是谁
Who exactly...?
时间领主
Time Lord.
什么
What?
对了 最后一位时间领主
Oh, yes! The last of the Time Lords.
和他的时光机器
And his travelling machine.
还有很久以前的人类女孩
With his little human girl from long ago.
听不懂你在说些什么 -时光旅行
Don't know what you're talking about. - Time travel!
有人骗了你
Someone's been telling you lies.
小伙子亚当·米切尔
Young master Adam Mitchell?
天呐 他的头
Oh, my God, his head...
他到底干了什么
What the hell's he done?
他去了哪 干了什么
What the hell's he gone and done?
他们在读取他的记忆
They're reading his mind,
他在告诉他们一切
he's telling them everything.
借由他 我就能掌握你们的一切
And through HIM, I know everything about YOU.
他脑中的一切信息都由我掌控了
Every piece of information in his head is now mine.
你确实有无穷无尽的知识 博士
And YOU have infinite knowledge, Doctor.
和你所见识过的相比
The Human Empire is tiny,
人类帝国非常渺小
compared to what you've seen in
你乘着你的 T.A.R.D.I.S
your T, A, R, D, I, S. . .
塔迪斯 -你别想碰到它
Tardis! - Well, you'll never get your hands on it,
除非我死了
I'll die first!
想死就死吧 反正也不需要你了
Well, die all you like, I don't need ya!
我有钥匙了
I've got the key!
你和你男朋友误大事了
You and your boyfriends!
今天 我们将成为头条
Today, WE are the headlines.
我们可以改写历史
We can re-write history.
可以阻止人类的发展进步
We could prevent mankind from developing.
没有人能够阻碍你
And no-one's gonna stop you.
因为你教唆了人类千万别多管闲事
Because you've bred a human race which doesn't bother to ask questions.
那群愚蠢的奴隶们相信你说的每个谎言
Stupid little slaves believing every lie.
他们会乖乖走进屠宰场
They'll just trot right into the
如果你告诉他们 那里的墙是金子做的
slaughterhouse if they're told it's made of gold.
解除安全系统
Disengage safety.
怎么回事
What's happening?
最大限度传输 接管139层
Maximum access, override Floor 139.
准备 接入
And... spike!
有人解除了安全系统
Someone's disengaged the safety.
是谁
Who's that?
是卡西卡 -她在思考
It's Cathica. - And she's thinking!
运用她所掌握的信息
She's using what she knows.
终止她的传输
Terminate her access!
所有我告诉她有关五号卫星的信息
Everything I told her about Satellite Five,
管道 过滤系统 她在反向传输中
the pipes, the filters, she's reversing it!
快看那 这里开始变热了
Look at that. It's getting hot.
我说过了 终止
I said, terminate!
烧焦她的大脑
Burn out her mind!
想都别想
Oh no, you don't!
你早就该升我的权限了
You should've promoted me years back!
她在往这传输热量
She's venting the heat up here.
加戈菲斯需要低温环境
The Jagrafess needs to stay cool
它现在感觉就像是坐在火山口
and now it's sitting on top of a volcano!
是的 阁下 我在努力
Oh, yes, I'm trying, sir,
我不知道她是怎么做到的 这不可能
but I don't know how she did it, it's impossible!
一位有思想的员工
A member of staff with an idea!
我该怎么做
What do I do?
按下开关
Flick the switch!
喂 想知道什么确定会发生吗
Oi, mate! You want to bank on a certainty?
大量热量 聚集在庞大的身躯内
Massive heat, in a massive body...
引发大爆炸
massive bang!
我们头条见
See you in the headlines!
阁下 其实我想要辞职
Actually, sir, if it's all the same to you,
对你来说没什么影响吧 再见
I think I'll resign. Bye, then.
放开我
Let go of me!
我们先撤了 我讨厌收拾烂摊子
We're just gonna go, I hate tidying up.
肯定会有很多问题 你能搞定的
Too many questions. You'll manage.
你们得留在这解释 没人会相信我的
You'll have to stay and explain it, no-one's gonna believe me.
为什么 他们相信很多事
Why, they might believe a lot of things.
人类应该会加速发展 回归正常
Human race should accelerate. All back to normal.
那你朋友呢 -他不是我朋友
What about your friend? - He's not my friend.
别…
Now, don't...
我没事了 好多了
I'm all right now. Much better.
钥匙也还在我这 就…
And I've got the key. Look, it's... and, well...
一切都完美解决了 不是吗
it all worked out for the best, didn't it?
这不是我的错 因为这一切都该你负责
You know it's not actually my fault because you were in charge.
这是我家
It's my house!
我回家了 天呐 我回家了
I'm home. Oh, my God, I'm home!
我还以为你要把我丢出舱外呢
Blimey. I thought you were gonna chuck me out of an airlock.
你还有什么事要跟我说的吗
Is there something else you want to tell me?
没有 为什么这么问
No. What d'you mean?
五号卫星的档案
The archive of Satellite Five.
稍微泄露一点都将改变世界
One second of that message could've changed the world.
就这样吧 再见
That's it then. See ya.
什么叫"再见" -就是再也不见
How d'you mean, "see ya"? - As in, goodbye.
那我怎么办 你不能就这么一走了之
What about me? You can't just go,
我的脑子里还植入有第二种芯片
I've got my head. I've got a chip type two,
我的脑袋会打开
my head opens!
像这样吗
What, like this?
别这样 -别哪样
Don't! - Don't do what?
住手
Stop it!
好了博士 够了 住手吧
All right now, Doctor. That's enough. Stop it.
谢谢
Thank you.
喂 -抱歉 我实在忍不住试试
Oi! - Sorry, I couldn't resist.
全部历史差点就因为你而改变
The whole of history could've changed because of you.
我只是想帮忙 -只是帮你自己吧
I just wanted to help. - You were helping yourself.
我道过歉了 我真的很抱歉
I've said I'm sorry, and I am, I really am.
你不能就这样丢下我 -我能
But you can't just leave me like this. - Yes, I can.
因为不管谁看到你这样的脑袋
'Cos if you show that head to anyone,
都会立马解剖你一探究竟
they'll dissect you in seconds.
你不得不低调过日子
You'll have to live a very quiet life.
远离麻烦 做个普通人
Keep out of trouble. Be average.
不引人注目 祝你好运
Unseen. Good luck.
我想和你一起
But I wanna come with you.
我只带最好的人
I only take the best.
我有洛斯了
I've got Rose.
洛斯 洛斯
Rose, Rose!
天呐
Oh, my God!
是谁呀
Who's that?
杰夫 是你吗 -妈 是我
Geoff, is that you? - It's me, Mum.
先别进来 稍等一会
Don't come in, wait there a minute.
天呐 你都没告诉我你要回家
Oh, my Lord! You never told me you were coming home!
等我先脱一下外套
Hold on, I'll just take my coat off!
你应该提前告诉我你要回来的
I wish you'd told me you were coming home.
洛斯 带我一起走吧
Rose, take me with you.
我可以准备你喜欢喝的茶
I would've got your favourite tea in.
是什么声音
What's that noise?
你没关后门吗
Have you left the back door open?
天呐 这么大一阵风
Blimey, there's a draught.
真是太惊喜了
What a surprise!
让我好好瞧瞧你
Oh, let me look at you.
六个月了 却好像昨天刚见过你
Aw, six months. It's like I saw you yesterday.
很有趣吧 时间流逝如弹指一挥间
Isn't it funny? The time goes by like that.
谨遵所命 但你要小心你所许的愿望
Your wish is my command, but be careful what you wish for.
下集预告
今天我父亲死了
The day my father died.
我还以为一整天都会阴沉沉的
I thought it would be grim and stormy,
但其实不过是普通的一天 天呐就是这里
it's just an ordinary day. Oh, gosh, this is it!
他不能就这样一个人死去
He can't die on his own!
我能再试试吗
Can I try again?
天呐 就是这里
Oh, gosh, this is it.
洛斯 不
Rose! No!
我又这样 又挑了个愚蠢的原始人旅伴
I did it again, I picked another stupid ape!
但我又没改变什么历史
It's not like I've changed history.
洛斯 有个原本应该死去的人现在还活着
Rose, there's a man alive in the world who wasn't alive before.
整个世界都会因为他而发生改变
The whole world's different because he's alive!
时间出现了裂口 它们是来给伤口消毒的
Time's been damaged and they've come to sterilise the wound.
洛斯 到教堂里去
Rose, get in the church!